now that we have seen flush stall and
forwarding as a solution for hazards in
a pipeline let's do a quiz to see if you
know when each should be used let us say
that we have a five-stage pipeline where
the first stage fetches the instruction
the second stage decodes the instruction
and reads the registers the third stage
the instruction does the AL operation
and a branch is resolved so we know
where it's going in the M stage loads
and stores access memory so at the end
of this stage a load will finally have a
value and finally the fifth stage writes
the result to the register here we have
some hazards first there is a control
Hazard after the branch we fetch two
wrong instructions before we fetch the
correct multiply instruction in this
case so the red ones are the ones that
are fetched incorrectly the question for
you is should be flush stall or forward
here put a check mark in each of these
three boxes depending on which one we do
here next next we have a data
dependence where the multiply is
producing the R1 result and the load
needs to use that as the memory address
put a check mark in each of these three
boxes depending on whether we need to
flush stall or forward the value in this
case and finally the load is producing
the value of R1 that this ad needs to
use so the question for you is should be
flush stall or forward in this case note
that in some cases more than one of
these needs to be used for Optimal
Performance to help you get started I'm
going to tell you that for data
dependencies as we said we never want to
use flushing so the real question is
just should you stall or forward